Guide to the Charles A. Hanna Collection circa 1822–1950 (bulk, circa 1900–1950) MS 3126
New-York Historical Society
Charles A. Hanna collection
circa 1822–1950 (bulk, circa 1900–1950)
New-York Historical Society
Hanna, Charles A. (Charles Augustus), 1863-1950
MS 3126
37.5 Linear feet in 37 boxes (22 records cartons, 15 flat boxes)
Research notes and publications on historical topics compiled by Charles Augustus Hanna (1863–1950), a banker and amateur historian whose interest in the region of his native Ohio produced "Historical Collections of Harrison County" (1900), "Ohio Valley Genealogies" (1900), and "The Wilderness Trail, or, The Ventures and Adventures of the Pennsylvania Traders on the Allegheny Path" (1911), all of which are represented by materials in the collection. Also present are 27 volumes of notes for his "The Scotch-Irish, or, The Scot in North Britain, North Ireland, and North America" (1902), as well as the contents of an 18-drawer card catalog of genealogical data on the Hanna and allied families of New Jersey and Pennsylvania.
Access Restrictions
Open to qualified researchers. This collection is stored offsite and advance notice is required for use. Please contact manuscripts@nyhistory.org prior to your research visit to coordinate access. Keep in mind that it will take between two (2) and five (5) business days for collections to arrive, and you should plan your research accordingly.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Gift of Elizabeth Harrison Hanna Howell and Mary Eleanor Hanna Adams, daughters of Charles A. Hanna, July 1950.
Arrangement
The collection is not processed. Except for slight adjustments (e.g., reuniting separated volumes), it remains largely in the physical order in which it was shelved, with each volume being assigned a sequence number (SN) between 1 and 164 (some numbers have been skipped). To facilitate access, the container list divides the collection intellectually in two series:
Series I.
Charles A. Hanna research notes and publications, circa 1900–1950
Series II.
Publications by others, 1822–1950
Biographical note
Banker Charles Augustus Hanna (1863–1950), chief examiner of the New York Clearing House, 1911–1940, was a native of Cadiz, Ohio. As a genealogist and amateur historian (with memberships in the New-York, New Jersey, Ohio, and Virginia Historical Societies), his interests focused primarily on the region of his birth. In 1900 he published "Historical Collections of Harrison County, in the state of Ohio, With Lists of the First Land-Owners, Early Marriages (to 1841), Will Records (to 1861), Burial Records of the Early Settlements, and Numerous Genealogies," and "Ohio Valley Genealogies: Relating Chiefly to Families in Harrison, Belmont and Jefferson Counties, Ohio, and Washington, Westmoreland, and Fayette Counties, Pennsylvania." These were followed in 1902 by "The Scotch-Irish, or, The Scot in North Britain, North Ireland, and North America," and 1911 by "The Wilderness Trail, or, The Ventures and Adventures of the Pennsylvania Traders on the Allegheny Path."
[This note is drawn from Hanna's obituary in "The New York Times," May 20, 1950, p. 15, and his entry in "Who Was Who in America," vol. 3 (1951–1960), p. 366. See also "The Charles A. Hanna Collection" in "The New-York Historical Society Quarterly," vol. 34, no. 4 (October 1950), p. 346.]
Related Materials
The New-York Historical Society holds these publications by Hanna:
• Historical collections of Harrison County: in the state of Ohio: with lists of the first land-owners, early marriages (to 1841), will records (to 1861), burial records of the early settlements, and numerous genealogies (1900); call no. Offsite F497.H5 H2
• Ohio Valley genealogies: relating chiefly to families in Harrison, Belmont and Jefferson Counties, Ohio, and Washington, Westmoreland, and Fayette Counties, Pennsylvania (1900); call no. Offsite F516 .H24
• The wilderness trail; or, The ventures and adventures of the Pennsylvania traders on the Allegheny path, 2 vols. (1911); call no. Offsite F152 .H24
Scope and Contents
As described on accession in "The New-York Historical Society Quarterly," vol. 34, no. 4 (October 1950), p. 346, "The 300 books and pamphlets presented by [Charles A. Hanna's] daughters relate mainly to Scotland and Ireland, Indians, and local history in Ohio, Pennsylvania, and New Jersey, reflecting his special interests. With them came five volumes of newspaper clippings relating to Cadiz and Harrison County, Ohio; Mr. Hanna's own annotated copy of his 'Historical Collections of Harrison County,' with letters and clippings laid in; and the typescript of his 'The Wilderness Trail,' with a scrapbook of clipped reviews of it, and photographic negatives he took in Pennsylvania in 1909, to illustrate the work. The collection of Mr. Hanna's notes and manuscripts includes 18 drawers filled with genealogical data on three-by-five cards; 30 volumes of genealogical charts, correspondence, and data of the Hanna, Howell, Adams and other New York, New Jersey, and Ohio families; and 25 volumes of typewritten records relating to Scotch-Irish in the Eastern States, principally in Pennsylvania."
Separated Materials
A number of titles from Hanna's personal collection were incorporated into the general New-York Historical Society Library holdings. These may be found by searching for the phrase "Charles A. Hanna" in BobCat, the library's online catalog.
Drafts (documents); Genealogies (histories); Newspaper clippings.; Photographs.; Research notes.; Typescripts.; Adams County (Pa.); Belmont County (Ohio); Cadiz (Ohio); Cumberland County (N.J.); Fayette County (Pa.); Harrison County (Ohio); Jefferson County (Ohio); Monmouth County (N.J.); Ohio River Valley -- History -- To 1795.; Pennsylvania -- History -- Colonial period, ca. 1600-1775.; Ulster (Northern Ireland and Ireland) -- History.; Washington County (Pa.); Westmoreland County (Pa.); Genealogy and local history.; Indians Of North America -- Ohio River Valley.; Indians Of North America -- Pennsylvania.; Scots-Irish -- United States.; Hanna (Family)
- Series I. Charles A. Hanna research notes and publications, circa 1900–1950
  Arrangement
  Listed alphabetically by title.
  - Adams-Hayward families (Offsite-box 4, Volume SN-10)
  - Akin, Bodwell, Howell, Martin, Prewitt families (Offsite-box 4, Volume SN-9)
  - Appraised Valuation of the Furnishings of the Residence of Charles A. Hanna, 15 Rockledge Road, Montclair, N.J. (1913) (Offsite-box 4, Volume SN-8)
  - [blank book with scattered, tipped-in photographs] (Offsite-box 18, Volume SN-129)
  - Bushnell (Offsite-box 1, Volume SN-7)
    Conservation note
    In poor condition.
  - Cadiz Ohio 1 (Offsite-box 12, Volume SN-62)
  - Cadiz Ohio 2 | Col. Joseph Holmes (Offsite-box 12, Volume SN-63)
  - Cadiz Ohio 3 (Offsite-box 12, Volume SN-64)
  - [correspondence] (Offsite-box 19, Volume SN-155)
  - Clarke | Fulton | Green | [L]atham | [T]racy | Nicoll (Offsite-box 15, Volume SN-88)
  - Cromwell, Williams, Hall Family + Murray, Wheeler, Harrison, Hanna, Howell (Offsite-box 4, Volume SN-13)
  - Finley Family vol. I (Offsite-box 1, Volume SN-4)
  - Finley Family vol. II (Offsite-box 1, Volume SN-5)
  - Gastonia [Data in Regard to the Family of Gaston] (Offsite-box 10, Volume SN-43)
  - Genealogical Files. Hanna and Allied Families. New Jersey and Pennsylvania Families [card catalog] (Offsite-box 21)
    Scope and Contents
    Drawer 01: "Family Genealogies: A-Da"
  - Genealogical Files. Hanna and Allied Families. New Jersey and Pennsylvania Families [card catalog] (Offsite-box 22)
    Drawer 02: "Family Genealogies: Da-La"
  - Genealogical Files. Hanna and Allied Families. New Jersey and Pennsylvania Families [card catalog] (Offsite-box 23)
    Drawer 03: "Family Genealogies: Le-Z"
  - Genealogical Files. Hanna and Allied Families. New Jersey and Pennsylvania Families [card catalog] (Offsite-box 24)
    Drawer 04: "Family Genealogies: Bushnell"
  - Genealogical Files. Hanna and Allied Families. New Jersey and Pennsylvania Families [card catalog] (Offsite-box 25, Identifier left half of box)
    Drawer 05: "Family Genealogies: Howell"
  - Genealogical Files. Hanna and Allied Families. New Jersey and Pennsylvania Families [card catalog] (Offsite-box 25, Identifier right half of box)
    Drawer 06: "Family Genealogies: Harrison-Hall"
  - Genealogical Files. Hanna and Allied Families. New Jersey and Pennsylvania Families [card catalog] (Offsite-box 26, Identifier left half of box)
    Drawer 07: "Maryland | Penna. Scotch-Irish"
  - Genealogical Files. Hanna and Allied Families. New Jersey and Pennsylvania Families [card catalog] (Offsite-box 26, Identifier right half of box)
    Drawer 08: "New Jersey Families: A-N"
  - Genealogical Files. Hanna and Allied Families. New Jersey and Pennsylvania Families [card catalog] (Offsite-box 27, Identifier left half of box)
    Drawer 09: "New Jersey Families: O-Z | N.J. Burials"
  - Genealogical Files. Hanna and Allied Families. New Jersey and Pennsylvania Families [card catalog] (Offsite-box 27, Identifier right half of box)
    Drawer 10: "Monmouth County, New Jersey | Other N.J."
  - Genealogical Files. Hanna and Allied Families. New Jersey and Pennsylvania Families [card catalog] (Offsite-box 28)
    Drawer 11: "Adams County, Penna. | Silver Spring Members | Middle Spring Members | Rocky Spr. Members"
  - Genealogical Files. Hanna and Allied Families. New Jersey and Pennsylvania Families [card catalog] (Offsite-box 29)
    Drawer 12: "Cumberland County Genealogies: A-Gi"
  - Genealogical Files. Hanna and Allied Families. New Jersey and Pennsylvania Families [card catalog] (Offsite-box 30)
    Drawer 13: "Cumberland County Genealogies: Gl-Mz"
  - Genealogical Files. Hanna and Allied Families. New Jersey and Pennsylvania Families [card catalog] (Offsite-box 31)
    Drawer 14: "Cumberland County Genealogies: Me-Y"
  - Genealogical Files. Hanna and Allied Families. New Jersey and Pennsylvania Families [card catalog] (Offsite-box 32)
    Drawer 15: "Cumberland County Penna. Taxables"
  - Genealogical Files. Hanna and Allied Families. New Jersey and Pennsylvania Families [card catalog] (Offsite-box 33, Identifier left half of box)
    Drawer 16: "Cumberland County, Cumberland Valley Taxables"
  - Genealogical Files. Hanna and Allied Families. New Jersey and Pennsylvania Families [card catalog] (Offsite-box 33, Identifier right half of box)
    Drawer 17: "Cumberland County, Hopewell Township Taxables"
  - Genealogical Files. Hanna and Allied Families. New Jersey and Pennsylvania Families [card catalog] (Offsite-box 34)
    Drawer 18: unlabeled.
  - Genealogical files [envelopes + miscellaneous loose material] (Offsite-box 20)
    Envelopes for families named
    • Adams
    • Akin
    • Akin, Howell
    • Bodwell
    • Bushnell, Martin
    • Cross, Kirkpatrick
    • Dawes, Prewitt
    • Hanna, Harrison, Hall
    • Skidmore
    • Taber
  - GEN[ealogies] (Offsite-box 3, Volume SN-60)
  - Gist family | Howell (Offsite-box 10, Volume SN-45)
  - Green | Clarke | Gaylord Loveland Vermandell[?] (Offsite-box 12, Volume SN-59)
  - [Hanna family.] Charles A. Hanna Family 1 (Offsite-box 11, Volume SN-14)
  - [Hanna family.] Hanna family 2 (Offsite-box 11, Volume SN-54)
  - [Hanna family.] Judge John Hanna Family 3 (Offsite-box 11, Volume SN-47)
  - Hanna Family | Finley | Robertson | Leonard (Offsite-box 4, Volume SN-2)
  - Harbord | Lawrence | Skidmore (Offsite-box 1, Volume SN-6)
  - Harrison County Ohio History (Offsite-box 12, Volume SN-55)
  - Harrison County History (Offsite-box 12, Volume SN-56)
  - Historical Collections of Harrison County, in the State of Ohio (1900) (Offsite-box 19, Volume SN-156)
  - Howard-Williams families (Offsite-box 4, Volume SN-11)
  - Howell (Offsite-box 4, Volume SN-12)
  - Howell I (Offsite-box 2, Volume SN-58)
  - Howell II (Offsite-box 2, Volume SN-48)
  - Howell III (Offsite-box 2, Volume SN-49)
  - [Howell, Blackwell, John Hanna families] (Offsite-box 1, Volume SN-1)
  - Howell Family | Chetwood Woodhull | Green | Clarke Latham | Pynchon | Trace [Tract?] (Offsite-box 10, Volume SN-44)
  - Howell Family | Chetwood Woodhull | Nicols (Offsite-box 10, Volume SN-46)
  - Josiah Stamp (Offsite-box 11, Volume SN-52)
  - Magazine [correspondence, clippings] (Offsite-box 15, Volume SN-89)
  - Martin-Sprague families (Offsite-box 2, Volume SN-50)
  - Photographs of Charles A. Hanna and Hanna family (Offsite-box 37)
  - Prewitt family (Offsite-box 3, Volume SN-90)
  - Rev. John Cuthbertson Journal, 1751-1790 (Offsite-box 10, Volume SN-41)
  - Rev. John Cuthbertson Journal, 1751-1790. Index (Offsite-box 10, Volume SN-42)
  - Roosevelt Blight x (Offsite-box 12, Volume SN-61)
  - Royal descent of Mrs. Harley Calvin Gage (Offsite-box 3, Volume SN-87)
  - Scotch-Irish in America, Vol. I. Pennsylvania (Offsite-box 5, Volume SN-15)
  - Scotch-Irish in America, Vol. II. Pennsylvania (Offsite-box 5, Volume SN-16)
  - Scotch-Irish in America, Vol. III. Pennsylvania (Offsite-box 5, Volume SN-17)
  - Scotch-Irish in America, Vol. IV. Pennsylvania (Offsite-box 5, Volume SN-18)
  - Scotch-Irish in America, Vol. V. Pennsylvania (Offsite-box 5, Volume SN-19)
  - Scotch-Irish in America, Vol. VI. Pennsylvania (Offsite-box 6, Volume SN-20a)
  - Scotch-Irish in America, Vol. VIII. Pennsylvania [EMPTY BINDER] (Offsite-box 6, Volume SN-20b)
  - Scotch-Irish in America, Vol. IX. Penna. Wills: Adams to Delaware Counties (Offsite-box 6, Volume SN-21)
  - Scotch-Irish in America, Vol. X. Penna. Wills: Franklin to Northumberland Counties (Offsite-box 6, Volume SN-22)
  - Scotch-Irish in America, Vol. XI. Penna. Wills: Philadelphia to Washington Counties (Offsite-box 6, Volume SN-23)
  - Scotch-Irish in America, Vol. XII. [spine label missing] (Offsite-box 6, Volume SN-24)
  - Scotch-Irish in America, Vol. XIII. Penna. Tax-Lists: Haccolee to Young (Offsite-box 7, Volume SN-25)
  - Scotch-Irish in America, Vol. XIV. Penna. Tax-Lists: Abbet to Byran (Offsite-box 7, Volume SN-26)
  - Scotch-Irish in America, Vol. XV. Penna. Tax-Lists: Cadwallader to Dysert (Offsite-box 7, Volume SN-27)
  - Scotch-Irish in America, Vol. XVI. [spine label missing] (Offsite-box 7, Volume SN-28)
  - Scotch-Irish in America, Vol. XVII. Penna. Tax-Lists: Hacket to Kyle (Offsite-box 7, Volume SN-29)
  - Scotch-Irish in America, Vol. XVIII. Penna. Tax-Lists: [partial label] (Offsite-box 8, Volume SN-30)
  - Scotch-Irish in America, Vol. XIX. [spine label missing] (Offsite-box 8, Volume SN-31)
  - Scotch-Irish in America, Vol. XX. Penna. Tax-Lists: [partial label] (Offsite-box 8, Volume SN-32)
  - Scotch-Irish in America, Vol. XXI. Penna. Tax-Lists: Ross to Temple (Offsite-box 8, Volume SN-33)
  - Scotch-Irish in America, Vol. XXII. Penna. Tax-Lists: Temple to Young (Offsite-box 8, Volume SN-34)
  - Scotch-Irish in America, Vol. XXIII. N.E., N.Y. (Offsite-box 9, Volume SN-35)
  - Scotch-Irish in America, Vol. XXIV. N.Y., N.J., M.D. (Offsite-box 9, Volume SN-36)
  - Scotch-Irish in America, Vol. XXV. Virginia (Offsite-box 9, Volume SN-37)
  - Scotch-Irish in America, Vol. XXVI. Nor. Carolina (Offsite-box 9, Volume SN-38)
  - Scotch-Irish in America, Vol. XXVII. So. Car., Geo. (Offsite-box 9, Volume SN-39)
  - Scraps (Offsite-box 11, Volume SN-51)
  - Ulster-Irish Society (Offsite-box 15, Volume SN-91)
  - Unsorted material (Offsite-box 36)
  - [volume without label] (Offsite-box 1, Volume SN-3)
  - Wilderness Trail (Offsite-box 10, Volume SN-40)
  - Wilderness Trail (Offsite-box 11, Volume SN-53)
  - Wilderness Trail, chapters 1–14 (Offsite-box 15, Volume SN-85)
  - Wilderness Trail, chapters 15–24 (Offsite-box 15, Volume SN-86)
  - Wilderness Trail illustrations (Offsite-box 36)
    45 prints of photographs taken in 1909 to illustrate Hanna's "The Wilderness Trail, or, The Ventures and Adventures of the Pennsylvania Traders on the Allegheny Path" (1911).
    Separated Materials
    108 negatives, possibly of nitrate stock, have been removed from the collection and placed in cold storage in the New-York Historical Society's conservation lab (freezer location B3).
  - Woodbridge and vicinity photostats (Offsite-box 12, Volume SN-57)
- Series II. Publications by others, 1822–1950
  Listed alphabetically by author or title.
  - Armstrong, William C. "The Battles in the Jerseys and the Significance of Each", 1916 (Offsite-box 19, Volume SN-149)
  - Authentic Librettos of the Wagner Operas, 1938 (Offsite-box 16, Volume SN-93)
  - Authentic Librettos of the Italian Operas, 1939 (Offsite-box 16, Volume SN-94)
  - Authentic Librettos of the French and German Operas, 1939 (Offsite-box 16, Volume SN-95)
  - Bartram, William. "Observations on the Creek and Cherokee Indians" (Offsite-box 18, Volume SN-139)
    Transactions of the American Ethnological Society, vol.III, part I (1853).
  - Beauchamp, William M. "Aboriginal Chipped Stone Implements of New York", 1897 (Offsite-box 17, Volume SN-110)
    Bulletin of the New York State Museum, vol. 4, no. 16 (October 1897).
  - Beauchamp, William M. "Aboriginal Occupation of New York", 1900 (Offsite-box 18, Volume SN-143)
    Bulletin of the New York State Museum, vol. 7, no. 32 (February 1900).
  - Beauchamp, William M. "Aboriginal Place Names of New York", 1907 (Offsite-box 18, Volume SN-142)
    New York State Museum Bulletin 108; Archeology [sic] 12.
  - Beauchamp, William M. "Aboriginal Use of Wood in New York", 1905 (Offsite-box 17, Volume SN-111)
    New York State Museum Bulletin 89, Archeology [sic] 11.
  - Beauchamp, William M. "Civil, Religious and Mourning Councils and Ceremonies of Adoption of the New York Indians", 1907 (Offsite-box 18, Volume SN-140)
    New York State Museum Bulletin 113; Archeology [sic] 13.
  - Beauchamp, William M. "The Iroquois Trail, or Foot-Prints of the Six Nations, in Customs, Traditions, and History", 1892 (Offsite-box 18, Volume SN-130)
  - Black, George Fraser. "Scotland's Mark on America", 1921 (Offsite-box 19, Volume SN-163)
  - Centennial Celebration of the United Presbyterian (The Old White) Church Building, Salem, Washington County, N.Y., November 9th, 1897, 1898 (Offsite-box 19, Volume SN-154)
  - Church Histories 2 (Offsite-box 13, Volume SN-65)
  - Church & Family Histories 3 (Offsite-box 13, Volume SN-66)
  - Church & Family Histories 4 (Offsite-box 13, Volume SN-67)
  - Clyde, Rev. John C. "Genealogies, Necrology, & Reminiscences of the 'Irish Settlement'", 1879 (Offsite-box 19, Volume SN-144)
  - The Critic: An Illustrated Monthly Review of Literature, Art & Life, vol. XL, no. 4, 1902 April (Offsite-box 16, Volume SN-98)
    Profile and photograph of Charles A. Hanna, p. 304.
  - Croll, Rev. P. C. "Annals of Womelsdorf, Pa. and Community, 1723–1923" (Offsite-box 19, Volume SN-151)
  - [Field, Thomas W.] "An Essay Towards an Indian Bibliography, Being a Catalogue of Books, Relating to the History, Antiquities, Languages, Customs, Religion, Wars, Literature, and Origin of the American Indians, in the Library of Thomas W. Field", 1873 (Offsite-box 18, Volume SN-132)
  - Fernald, James C., comp. "Helpful Hints in English", 1911 (Offsite-box 19, Volume SN-148)
  - Gilpin, William J., and Henry E. Wallace. "Clearing House of New York City, 1854–1905", 1904 (Offsite-box 18, Volume SN-127)
  - Gravier, Gabriel. "Carte des Grands Lacs de l'Amérique du Nord dressée en 1670 par Bréhan de Gallinée", 1895 (Offsite-box 18, Volume SN-138)
  - Greg, W. W. "A Bibliography of the English Printed Drama to the Restoration," vol. II, 1951 (Offsite-box 14, Volume SN-84)
  - Hartshorne, Richard. "The Monmouth Patent. An Addressed [sic] Delivered by Judge Richard Hartshorne at the Presentation of a Commemorative Tablet to the Monmouth Historical Association, at Freehold, N.J., May 10, 1946" (Offsite-box 19, Volume SN-150)
  - Historical Pamphlets 1 (Offsite-box 13, Volume SN-68)
  - Historical Pamphlets 2 (Offsite-box 13, Volume SN-69)
  - Historical Pamphlets 3 (Offsite-box 13, Volume SN-70)
  - Historical Pamphlets 4 (Offsite-box 13, Volume SN-71)
  - Historical Pamphlets 5 (Offsite-box 13, Volume SN-72)
  - Historical Pamphlets 6 (Offsite-box 13, Volume SN-73)
  - Historical Pamphlets 7 (Offsite-box 13, Volume SN-74)
  - Hugo, Victor. "Hernani", 1907 (Offsite-box 16, Volume SN-107)
  - Irish Heraldry. Coats of Arms of Eleven Hundred Irish Family Names, Executed from Descriptions Contained in O'Hart's Irish Pedigrees, Fairbairn's Crests, Burke's Peerage, Fox-Davies Armorial Bearings, etc., etc., Including Crests and Mottoes, 1930 (Offsite-box 19, Volume SN-159)
  - Kelley, Frank Bergen, comp. "Historic Elizabeth, 1664–1914" (Offsite-box 19, Volume SN-153)
  - "Kittochtinny Magazine," vol. 1, bound with "Papers Read Before the Kittochtinny Historical Society, March 1903–February 1905" (Offsite-box 18, Volume SN-133)
  - Marshe, Witham. "Lancaster in 1744. Journal of the Treaty at Lancaster in 1744, with the Six Nations", 1884 (Offsite-box 18, Volume SN-136)
  - Melish, John. "The Traveller's Directory Through the United States; Containing a Description of All the Principal Roads Through the United States, with Copious Remarks on the Rivers, and Other Objects", 1822 (Offsite-box 19, Volume SN-145)
  - Messler, Rev. A. "First Things in Old Somerset, A Collection of Articles Relating to Somerset County, N.J.", 1899 (Offsite-box 18, Volume SN-134)
  - Moore, Charles. "The Gladwin Manuscripts, with an Introduction and a Sketch of the Conspiracy of Pontiac", 1897 (Offsite-box 18, Volume SN-137)
  - Nelson, William. "Personal Names of Indians of New Jersey: Being a List of Six Hundred and Fifty Such Names, Gleaned Mostly from Indian Deeds of the Seventeenth Century", 1904 (Offsite-box 19, Volume SN-160)
  - New York Genealogical and Biographical Record, vol. XVII, no. 2, 1886 April (Offsite-box 16, Volume SN-96)
  - New York Genealogical and Biographical Record, vol. LXVII, no. 1, 1936 January (Offsite-box 16, Volume SN-97)
  - Nugent, Nell Marion. "Cavaliers and Pioneers: Abstracts of the Virginia Land Patents and Grants, 1623-1800," vol. 1, 1934 (Offsite-box 18, Volume SN-131)
  - "Old Northwest" Genealogical Quarterly, vol. 1, 1898 (Offsite-box 17, Volume SN-112)
  - "Old Northwest" Genealogical Quarterly, vol. 2, 1899 (Offsite-box 17, Volume SN-113)
  - "Old Northwest" Genealogical Quarterly, vol. 3, 1900 (Offsite-box 17, Volume SN-114)
  - "Old Northwest" Genealogical Quarterly, vol. 4, 1901 (Offsite-box 17, Volume SN-115)
  - "Old Northwest" Genealogical Quarterly, vol. 5, 1902 (Offsite-box 17, Volume SN-116)
  - "Old Northwest" Genealogical Quarterly, vol. 6, 1903 (Offsite-box 17, Volume SN-117)
  - "Old Northwest" Genealogical Quarterly, vol. 7, 1904 (Offsite-box 17, Volume SN-118)
  - "Old Northwest" Genealogical Quarterly, vol. 8, 1905 (Offsite-box 17, Volume SN-119)
  - "Old Northwest" Genealogical Quarterly, vol. 9, 1906 (Offsite-box 17, Volume SN-120)
  - "Old Northwest" Genealogical Quarterly, vol. 10, 1907 (Offsite-box 17, Volume SN-121)
  - "Old Northwest" Genealogical Quarterly, vol. 11, 1908 (Offsite-box 17, Volume SN-122)
  - "Old Northwest" Genealogical Quarterly, vol. 12, 1909 (Offsite-box 17, Volume SN-123)
  - "Old Northwest" Genealogical Quarterly, vol. 13, 1910 (Offsite-box 17, Volume SN-124)
  - "Old Northwest" Genealogical Quarterly, vol. 14, 1911 (Offsite-box 17, Volume SN-125)
  - "Old Northwest" Genealogical Quarterly, vol. 15, 1912 (Offsite-box 17, Volume SN-126)
  - One Hundred Americans [engraved portraits of historical figures] (Offsite-box 15, Volume SN-92)
  - Parker, Arthur C. "Excavations in an Erie Indian Village and Burial Site at Ripley, Chautauqua Co., N.Y.", 1907 (Offsite-box 18, Volume SN-141)
    New York State Museum Bulltein 117; Archeology [sic] 14.
  - Porter, Peter A. "A Brief History of Old Fort Niagara", 1896 (Offsite-box 16, Volume SN-109)
  - Reid, Whitelaw. "The Scot in America, and the Ulster Scot", 1911 (Offsite-box 18, Volume SN-135)